Guide to the Yale Law School Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of the dean of the Yale Law School, 1871-1994; Accession 2001-A-040
  - Dean Eugene V. Rostow, Assist. Dean Charles Runyon, Dean Wesley Sturges, Assoc. Dean Jack B. Tate -Scholarship information files, A-O, 1951-1963
    - American Steel Foundries Foundation, 410 North Michigan Ave., Chicago 11, Ill., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - The Brown-Brockmeyer Foundation; 1000 South Smithville Road, Dayton 3, Ohio, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Carnegie Endowment For Int. Peace, 1962 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Commercial Bank Loans For Education; 1stNew Haven in File, 1959 (Box 68)
      - Application, Brochures, Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - TheConnecticutHigher Education Assistance Corporation, 1959-1962 (Box 68)
      - Act, Brochures, Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Report (Box 68)
    - C. Cowles and Company, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - East European Fund, Inc., The, undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
    - Fellowships offered by Foreign Governments, Universities and (Box 68)
    - General Education Board, undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
    - Greycloud Foundation; Smoke Rise, New Jersey, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Haffenreffer Benevolent Corporation, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Yale Scholarship ForHawaii, 1956, 1958-1959 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Notes (Box 68)
    - HowardHeinzEndowment; P. O. Box 926, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Draft, Gen. Correspondence, Notes (Box 68)
    - International Federation of Women Lawyers, 1960 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - International Harvester Foundation; 180 North Michigan Ave., Chicago 1, Ill., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - MassachusettsScholarship, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Memo (Box 68)
    - Meyer Institute of Law, 1963 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo, Minutes, Reports (Box 68)
    - National Scholarship Service and Fund for Negro Students, 6 East 82ndStreet, New York 28, New York, 1959 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - New YorkCommunity Trust, 1958-1959 (Box 68)
      - Booklet, Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - New YorkHigher Education Assistance Corporation, 1958-1960 (Box 68)
      - Application, Booklet, Gen. Correspondence, Lists, Memo, Press Release (Box 68)
    - New York Times Foundation, undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
  - Dean Wesley Sturges, Assist. Deans Charles Runyon and Clare J. Sturges, Assoc. Dean Jack B. Tate - Scholarship information files, Misc., P-Z, 1947-1949, 1951-1962
    - Committee of thePermanentCharity Fund, 100 Franklin Street, Boston 10, Massachusetts, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - PhiDelta Phi - Legal Fraternity, 1957-1958 (Box 68)
      - Personal Correspondence; The Brief quarterly, Fall 1957 and Spring 1958 (Box 68)
    - Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity Fellowship, 1960 (Box 68)
      - Memo, Statement of Account (Box 68)
    - Two-Way Fellowship, 1947-1949, 1960 (Box 68)
      - Drafts, Gen. Correspondence, Lists, Memos, Statements of Account (Box 68)
    - Banks Now Prepared To Accept Applications for Student Loans Under NYHEAC Program, 1958 (Box 68)
      - List (Box 68)
    - Scholarships For Ill. Residents, Inc., c/o Alfred N. Guertin, 230 N. Michigan Ave., Chicago 1, Ill., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - ScholarshipsFoundation Inc., undated (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Note Card (Box 68)
    - Service League Foundation, Inc., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - SheerrFoundation, Inc., 1500 Chestnut Street, 12thFloor, Philadelphia 2, Pa., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Sloan, Alfred P. Foundation, Inc. School of Industrial Management, 1960 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Social Research Foundation, Inc., undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
    - Stevens Bros. Foundation, Inc., 1962 (Box 68)
      - Applications/Questionnaires (Box 68)
    - Stich Charitable Foundation, Inc., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Stone Charitable Foundation, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Travelers Broadcasting Service Corp. WTIC, 1961 (Box 68)
      - Press Release (Box 68)
    - United States Rubber Co., undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
    - Van Amerigen Fndn., Inc., undated (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
    - Wagnalls Memorial, Inc., The Lithopolis, Ohio, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - The Frederick E. Weber Charities Corporation, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - WoodburyLaw Scholarship Dartmouth, 1951, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo (Box 68)
    - World University Service, 1958, 1960-1961 (Box 68)
      - Brochure, Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Statements of Account (Box 68)
    - Yale ClubScholarship Committee, 1958 (Box 68)
      - Brochure (Box 68)
    - Yale Alumni Association of Montclair, New Jersey, 1959 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence/Memo (Box 68)
    - Yale Law School Association of Canada, 1960 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Y. M. and Y. W. C. A., 1958 (Box 68)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
    - Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A., 1949 (Box 68)
      - Note Card (Box 68)
  - The Commonwealth of Massachusetts, Board of Educational Assistance, 200 Newbury Street, Boston 16, Massachusetts, 1958 (Box 68)
    - Applications, Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Statements of Account (Box 68)
  - Raymond Rich Associates, 1958 (Box 68)
    - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
  - Vocational Advisory Service, 1951 (Box 68)
    - Gen. Correspondence (Box 68)
  - Connecticut and Rhode Island Supplement to American Foundations and Their Fields VII, 1957 (Box 68)
    - Booklet (Box 68)
  - Indiana Supplement to American Foundations and Their Fields VII, 1958 (Box 68)
    - Booklet (Box 68)
  - Michigan Supplement to American Foundations and Their Fields VII, 1957 (Box 68)
    - Booklet (Box 68)
  - New Jersey Supplement to American Foundations and Their Fields VII, 1957, 1959 (Box 68)
    - Booklets (Box 68)
  - Supplement for North Carolina and South Carolina, 1959 (Box 68)
    - Booklet (Box 68)
  - New England Higher Education Assistance Foundation, 1958-1959 (Box 69)
    - Annual Report, Brochures, Gen. Correspondence, Newsletter (Box 69)
  - MassachusettsHigher Education Assistance Corporation, 1956-1958 (Box 69)
  - The National Defense Education Act of 1958, Literature and Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 69)
    - Booklets, Brochures, Journal, Memos, Notes, Oaths and Affidavits, Press Releases, Promissory Notes, Registry Forms, Yale Daily News (Box 69)
  - National Defense Act of 1958 (Box 69)
    - Gen. Correspondence, Memo, Newspaper Clipping, Proposal (Box 69)
  - The Crippled Children's Friendly Aid Association Scholarship, Old Scholarships and Correspondence, 1951 (Box 69)
  - Scholarships, Old Scholarships and Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 69)
    - Lists, Memos, Scholarship Awards (Box 69)
  - New Jersey State Foundation of Women's Clubs, Old Scholarships and Correspondence, 1957 (Box 69)
    - Statement of Account (Box 69)
  - The Yale Law School Association of Washington D.C., Old Scholarships and Correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 69)
    - Lists, Memos (Box 69)
  - Dean Eugene V. Rostow and Assist. Dean Charles Runyon - African Program subject files, 1957 - 1963
    - Foreign Students -- Programs and services for, 1961-1963 (Box 69)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Legal Education overseas - Graduate Studies, 1961 - 1962 (Box 70)
      - Reports (Box 70)
    - Graduate Studies, 1957 - 1958, 1962 - 1963 (Box 70)
      - Applications, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Graduate Students, 1957 - 1963 (Box 70)
      - Memos, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Continuing Legal Education, 1959 (Box 70)
      - Drafts, Memos, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Operation Impetus,Correspondence and Notes, 1963 (Box 70)
    - Program for Cooperation in African Legal Education and Research, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
    - Memos, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Origins of LS African Work, 1961 (Box 70)
      - Drafts, Memos, Minutes, Misc. Correspondence, Notes, Proposals (Box 70)
    - Meeting at Yale, 1961 April 212 (Box 70)
    - This was start of program and sailer - Staffing of African (Box 70)
    - Institutions of Legal Education and Research (Box 70)
    - Operation Impetus, Memoranda and Documents, 1963 (Box 70)
      - Drafts, Proposals, Notes (Box 70)
    - Operation Impetus, Visits on, 1963 May 3-4 (Box 70)
      - Memos, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - University of the Philippines - College of Law, 1962 - 1963 (Box 70)
      - Misc. Correspondence, Program Documents (Box 70)
    - Yale Areas Program and its African Comm., 1960 - 1962 (Box 70)
      - Memos, Misc, Correspondence, Notes (Box 70)
    - Correspondence Names Transcripts and Resumes (Box 70)
      - Gottesman, A. E. and Amer. Comm. on Foreign Law, 1961 (Box 70)
      - Applicants to go to Africa A-G, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
      - Applicants to go to Africa H-M, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
      - Applicants to go to Africa N-S, 1961 - 1962 (Box 70)
      - Pauli Murray, 1962 (Box 70)
      - Applicants to go to Africa T-Z, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
    - German Universities, 1963 (Box 70)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Books for Law Teaching in Africa - #61-42-10-1040, 1962 - 1963 (Box 70)
      - Account Information, Memos, Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
    - Program for Cooperation in African Legal Education and Research, 1961 - 1962 (Box 70)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 70)
  - Deans Eugene V. Rostow and Charles Runyon and Assist. Dean Henry V. Poor - African Program subject files
    - Ghana, 1961-1963 (Box 70)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Resumes, Telegram (Box 71)
    - Ibingira, 1962 - 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo, Telegram (Box 71)
    - Institute of International Education Africa Project, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Khartoum, 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Booklet, Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Telegram (Box 71)
    - Liberia, 1961 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Africa Library Matters, 1961 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Lists, Memos (Box 71)
    - Universite Lovanium, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence written in French (Box 71)
    - MIT, 1960 - 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Lists, Memos, Notes (Box 71)
    - Medico Incorporated, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Brochures, Gen. Correspondence, Map (Box 71)
    - Michigan State, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Michigan Univ., 1960 (Box 71)
      - Booklet (Box 71)
    - New York University, no date (Box 71)
      - Note (Box 71)
    - Africa - General, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - African American Institute, 1960 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Annual Report, Gen. Correspondence, Notes (Box 71)
    - African Scholarship Program for American Universities, circa 1962 (Box 71)
      - Brochure (Box 71)
    - A. I. D., I. C. A. - International Cooperation Administration, 1960 - 1961 (Box 71)
      - Booklets, Gen. Correspondence, Memo, Pamphlet (Box 71)
    - Ahmadu Bello University, 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Note (Box 71)
    - Nigeria, 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Pamphlet (Box 71)
    - Northwestern Coons, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, List (Box 71)
    - Nyasaland, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Operation Crossroads Africa, Inc., 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - P. A. C. E., Project for the Advancement of Cultural Exchange, circa 1961 (Box 71)
      - Project Notes (Box 71)
    - Peace Corps Seminar, 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Programs (Box 71)
    - Peace Corps, 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, List, Memos, Note (Box 71)
    - Rutgers, 1961 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Proposal (Box 71)
    - SAILER, Staffing of African Institutions of Legal Education and Research, 1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo (Box 71)
    - Sierra Leone, 1960 - 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Syllabus (Box 71)
    - Somalia, circa 1962 (Box 71)
      - Biography Prof. Bentivoglio (Box 71)
    - Republic of South Africa, 1960 - 1961 (Box 71)
      - Booklets, Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Southern Cameroon, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Southern Rodesia and Nyasaland, 1961 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - State Department, 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Resume (Box 71)
    - Syracuse 1961-1962 Ac. Yr., 1961 - 1964 (Box 71)
      - Agendas, Applications, Brochures, Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Minutes, Notes, Reports (Box 71)
    - United Nations, 1961 - 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo (Box 71)
    - American Bar Association, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Draft, Gen. Correspondence, Proposal (Box 71)
    - American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc., 1963 (Box 71)
      - Brochure, Memo (Box 71)
    - American Foreign Law Association, 1961 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Assoc. of Univ. of the British Commonwealth, 1960 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Boston University, circa 1960 (Box 71)
      - Information from Boston University Bulletin (Box 71)
    - Carnegie, 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Draft/Proposal, Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Chicago U., 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - The Congo, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Press Release (Box 71)
    - Mr. Stevens' Copy - Denning Comm. Report '61 Eisenhower Fellowships, 1961 - 1964 (Box 71)
      - Brochure, Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Notes (Box 71)
    - Ethiopia, 1962 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 71)
    - Ford, 1961-1963 (Box 71)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Grant, Memos, Notes (Box 71)
  - Deans Louis H. Pollak, Eugene V. Rostow, Wesley Sturges and Assoc. Dean Jack B. Tate - Faculty appointments, A-L, 1948 - 1965
    - Re - New Personnel and Recommendations, 1957 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Resumes (Box 72)
    - Abrams, 1960 (Box 72)
      - Memo/Resume (Box 72)
    - Albright - follow up, 1960 - 1961 (Box 72)
      - Memo, Recommendation for Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Barber, 1964 (Box 72)
      - Bibliography, Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Recommendation for Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Bicks, 1961 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memo, Recommendation for Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Recommendation for Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Blum, 1959 November (Box 72)
      - Memo (Box 72)
    - Letter Excerpt (Box 72)
    - Booklet article, Letter Excerpt, Gen. Correspondence (Box 72)
    - Gen. Correspondence, Resume (Box 72)
    - Devlin Party - Law School Acceptances, 1956 - 1965 (Box 72)
      - Announcement, Gen. Correspondence, Notes (Box 72)
    - Eyster, 1960 - 1964 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Personnel Forms, Recommendation for Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Fatouros, 1962 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 72)
    - Feinsinger, 1961 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 72)
    - Finman, 1961 (Box 72)
      - Memos (Box 72)
    - Foote, Caleb, 1952, 1955 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Letter Excerpt, Memo, Note (Box 72)
    - A. W. Ford, 1957 - 1958 (Box 72)
      - Biography, Gen. Correspondence, Memos (Box 72)
    - Fyzee, 1957 (Box 72)
      - Memos (Box 72)
    - Harbaugh, 1960 - 1961, 1964 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Note, Resume (Box 72)
    - Hellawell, 1957, 1964 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Resume (Box 72)
    - Hopkins, Dean Bert E., 1955 - 1957 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Note, Recommendation of Academic Appointment (Box 72)
    - Kennedy, undated (Box 72)
      - Bibliography (Box 72)
    - Klemme, 1960 (Box 72)
      - Memos (Box 72)
    - Knutson, 1958 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 72)
    - Krasnowiecki, 1961 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence (Box 72)
    - Yuval Levy, 1960 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Recommendation for Academic Appointment, Resume (Box 72)
    - Linde, Hans, 1957 - 1958 (Box 72)
      - Gen. Correspondence, Resume (Box 72)
    - Gen. Correspondence, Notes, Recommendation for Academic (Box 72)
    - Appointment (Box 72)
    - Gen. Correspondence, Memos, Notes (Box 72)
  - Deans Louis H. Pollak and Eugene V. Rostow - Misc. subject files, 1959 - 1966
    - Yale Law Journal, 1964-1965 (Box 73)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 73)
    - Marts and Lundy Agreement, 1963 (Box 73)
    - Student Association, 1964 - 1965 (Box 73)
    - Student Association, 1964 (Box 73)
    - Law Journal, Summer Research, 1965 - 1966 (Box 73)
    - Legal Aid, 1959 - 1963 (Box 73)
      - Misc. Correspondence, Reports (Box 73)
    - Dean's Report, 1962 - 1965 (Box 73)
      - Misc. Correspondence (Box 73)
    - Law Students Civil Rights Research Council, 1964 - 1965 (Box 73)
  - Yale Law School Student Register Oversize (Box 73)
    - 1909- (Box 74)
    - 1873-; Grade Book, 1873-. (Box 75)
  - Examination Records Oversize, 1900- (Box 76)
  - Yale Law School Attendance Records Oversize (Box 76)
    - 1902-1909; 1897- (Box 77)
    - 1924-, 1933- (Box 78)
  - Yale Law School Student Register, 1944 Summer Term, Third Year, Sixth Term - 1947 Fall Term, First Year, First Term Oversize; Attendance Records Oversize, 1902-., 1902-1947 (Box 79)
  - Yale Law School Alumni Record - Classes Graduated at the Yale Law School in 1916 June; Examination Records Oversize, 1896-1899; Plaque - The Roscoe Pound Foundation, YLS, 1992, 1896-1992 (Box 80)
- Eugene Rostow, dean of the Yale Law School, records, 1958-1959; Accession 2008-A-183
  The materials are open for research, except for box 2, folder 18 where these records are restricted until January 1, 2035.
  - Correspondence
    - I, J, K, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - L, M, N, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - O - R, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - S, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - T - Z, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Subject files
    - ABA, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Addiction project, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Administration - general, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Alumni day, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Alumni meetings, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - American Law Institute, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Arbitration Appointmetns (RCA), 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Arbitration committee, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Arpaia - Library letters, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Association of American Law Schools, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Bulletin board and notices to faculty, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Malone - correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Prospective faculty, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      These records are restricted until January 1, 2035.